Good morning.
Who's afraid of robots?
Afraid of robots? Afraid of robots?
Uh
I'm not afraid of robots because they
have already bloodied my nose so many
times. There's no more pain that they
can give to me.
And that is what I want to tell you
about
on this fine morning.
Thanks for coming to hang with me.
So, my name is Danilo. I work at
PostHog, and I make the PostHog Wizard.
And the very strange thing that the
PostHog Wizard does
is it skips 2 hours of misery that you
will never get back in your life,
and it hands it back to you
as 8 minutes
of pseudo entertainment.
Now,
how do we get away with this?
We're talking 15,000
people
every single month run this wizard,
and in exchange for their trouble, they
get a PostHog integration that works and
that they actually like.
How do we do it?
I'm going to tell you all about it
today.
And
just to underscore the point that this
actually works,
in the last 6 hours,
we got two
unprompted posts on Blue Sky and Twitter
where people are actually happy.
Now, this should be terrifying, right? I
got a robot out there. It's writing code
for people.
What if it's doing a bad job?
Well, we learned all the ways that it
could do a bad job. I'm going to tell
you the ways
that those bad jobs happen. I'm going to
tell you some strategies that you can
use
so that your autonomous coding agents do
the right thing
as well.
All right. Let's start with the easy
one.
We've got model rot.
Now, training a model takes a lot of
time,
but it's not even the time, it's the
it's the money, right? You're not
screwing around as Anthropic training a
model on a weekend as a lark, right?
This is serious capital expense.
And the trade-off with this is that the
models sit there no longer representing
reality, right? They are a snapshot of
the world and the web as it was, you
know, 6, 8, 12, 18 months ago, perhaps.
Now, this is useful for many things, but
if you are fast-moving software project,
and there are loads of fast-moving
software projects,
the trade-off of this is that the model
doesn't know what the hell is going on
anymore.
So, you got to deal with model rot.
Now, this is fairly straightforward
stuff. You've probably dealt with this
sort of thing before.
Does anyone here have a conviction about
how you deal with model rot?
Any guesses?
I'm seeing I'm seeing some shaking
heads. What's that?
>> Rags.
>> Rags is good.
>> Yeah.
>> Although, I'll tell you what,
with the context windows being what they
are at this point, you can't beat just
shoving a bunch of markdown files into
the context and patching the holes. And
this is exactly what we do,
uh, with the PostHog wizard, is that we
have documentation that is fresh, hot
off the presses on posthog.com,
and we allow the agent to make a
selection. We say, "Hey, what are you
doing? What are you integrating right
here? What have we detected?"
And the agent can use tools to go out,
pick from a menu of fresh hot markdown
that it can then just slide right into
its context, get the job done, do things
correctly. Now,
what happened to spur all of this was
that a year ago, people started asking
their very primitive agents, like, "All
right, Cursor, I want you to integrate
PostHog for me."
And it would do a terrible job, right?
It's just it's making up keys, it is
making up patterns, it is inventing APIs
that don't exist.
And it is is not our fault, like we
didn't do anything,
but it was our problem.
So, figuring out ways that we could
serve correct, up-to-date context
to the agent so that it would do the
correct job
is part of how we get people posting
happy
about what the wizard did for them.
All right.
Now,
these models, I mean, clearly they've
been scraping every kind of project out
there, and I have to guess that not all
of them had great architecture, because
some of the decisions that these agents
make when they're putting a project
together
are very strange.
Uh and so, what do you do? How do you
deal with the fact that an agent's
conception of how to put something
together may be technically like
workable,
but not exactly ideal.
Well,
me and my homies on the PostHog wizard
team,
we maintain a fleet of what we call
model airplanes.
And these are projects that have PostHog
implemented in them. They've got them
across a bunch of frameworks, a bunch of
languages.
But what makes it a model airplane is
that we don't have an entire proper
production application going in there.
What we have is something much thinner.
Something that is a simulacrum of a real
application, but for example, the off
doesn't work.
Or rather, the off works for anything.
You can just put whatever you want in
the password field and you're going to
be able to log in.
But the off is off-shaped, which means
that we can provide these model
airplanes to the agent. And then the
agent knows, "Oh, cool. So when off
shows up, this is a great place to put
the particular event tracking that one
would want to use
when they wanted to track logins and
identity in PostHog."
And so, through the maintenance of a
thing that isn't quite as elaborate as
the real production application, which
means also, of course, it is more token
efficient, what you get is the correct
shape of an integration as a pattern
that the model and agent are able to
complete consistently every time.
All right.
So,
in addition to weird architecture,
the agent can find a weird path through
the problem space. And with 15,000
integrations per month, it might find
15,000
ways to get a PostHog integration done.
And while this would satisfy the
requirements of we've automated
integration, it would leave us with a
very strange support burden because we
would have too many different ways that
PostHog was set up. It's like, "What
what what the hell is this? How do I
make sense of this?" Right? This would
be a problem at scale. This would be
some sorcerer's apprentice stuff.
So,
to limit improvisation,
what we do is breadcrumb the agent. We
don't tell the agent up front exactly
what we're going to do.
You know, maybe you've seen this before
even when you're using Claude code is
that if you tell them exactly where you
want to go, it might make a Claude
code-shaped hole through the first four
tasks and then just get really rock
polishy with the fifth, right? And this
is not what we want for our case.
And so one of the things that we do is
we start off barely even telling the
agent that this is what we're doing. We
don't even mention really that we're
doing a PostHog integration.
We start with something like
where are the files
with interesting business value in this
project?
Can you find something that looks like a
login or a Stripe interface or something
that might indicate someone's about to
churn? All right, we go looking for the
files that would be responsive to impact
in somebody's business. And the funny
thing is that business stuff casts a
huge shadow in code. And so we can very
reliably detect this kind of stuff.
Now, from there, we say, "Okay, here are
some cool files. What are the
interesting events going on in those
files? Don't write any code right now.
Just let Let's think about some cool
events that we might want to sprinkle
through here. What might those be?"
So, we make a list of these. And we get
the event names. We get the descriptions
for those events. And we just tuck them
into a little file.
And this is the start of things, right?
Like we don't even know where we're
going necessarily. And so the next
breadcrumb is like, "Okay,
let's start to actually implement
PostHog. We now know a bunch of events
and we've really thought carefully about
what those events might be. And now we
have documentation and everything, which
we can load
at whim according to the framework and
language that we care about here.
And so we can reliably go in there and
start to make modifications to people's
files and the modifications are once
again not stupid
and and they're not mad about it.
Okay.
Now,
we can do all of the thoughtful stuff
that we can to
make the agent successful. But, the
biggest threat to our agent outcomes is
ourselves. We're we're we're feeble
little beings. We got a little bit of
meat right here locked inside of our
heads, and we have a context limit, too.
We can't really quantify it, and it
varies by how long ago we had some
coffee, and if we had breakfast that
morning.
Our context is not just limited, but
fragmentary. There's stuff that we
remember implementing last week, and
there's stuff that we forgot from last
month.
And so, we're making changes, and we're
editing code, and we're evolving the
stuff that our agent is working around,
and sometimes we are dropping things
that really matter.
And so, there is a point where we had an
MCP
tool instruction that was contradictory
to a different tool.
And the agent is like, "Man, I don't
know what to do here. You're you're
you're putting me into an impossible
spot."
Um we had um a situation where we were
telling it, "Hey, there is a tool that
you definitely need to use to conclude
this setup." And the agent is going,
"All right, cool. Let's Let's use the
tool. Wait, the the MCP does not have a
tool by this name."
And we're talking like hundreds of runs
going with this missing tool.
And
what's going on there?
So,
if we didn't ask, we wouldn't know.
And so, one of the things that you can
do that is really handy and fairly cheap
is a little bit of inference time
interrogation of what just happened with
your agent. So, at the end of every run,
uh right at the stop hook, we ask a very
simple question. We're doing a little
bit of user research, but the user is in
this case a robot. And we ask the the
robot user, "Hey,
what could we have done
better to set you up for success in this
run.
And then it tells us, and that's how we
found out. Like, "Oh, you we
We didn't give you permission to access
the tool." And so, there was no tool.
"Hey, you've got these contradictory
directives."
Um without this ongoing interrogation uh
Oh, a good one is that we kept giving it
instructions for JavaScript, and it was
a Python project that it was working in.
Um of course, very um
well, not frustrating, but, you know, we
would identify it that way. Um so, the
human error, big deal.
You have to ask to find out.
Now,
there's also shenanigans that you got to
be concerned about here because running
an agent on someone else's machine
demands a huge amount of trust, right?
We we we've got this robot that could do
anything potentially, and we don't want
to do something uh bad or destructive to
the user's project. We don't want to put
them in a worse spot.
Um and one of the early versions of our
wizards would actually just read .env
files, which is necessary to do writes,
right? You can't just write blind to a
file. It's just one of the mechanics of
how, you know, these agents work.
But, it's also not ideal to be sending
people's ENV contents up to a cloud, and
it's like, "All right, cool. That's
sitting in someone's damn log that you
don't know about."
Um so, this is obviously bad news.
But, when you're designing these things,
you have fine-grained control over tool
usage, right? You can decide, "All
right, these tools are okay. These kinds
of reads are okay. These kinds of reads
are not okay." So, we really locked down
what the agent was allowed to do around
anything that was an ENV file.
And then we were able to build it a tool
that could do two things. It could check
the presence of a key.
Does this key exist?
And it could write to a key a new value.
And that was it. There was nothing that
was going up in terms of inference for
this ENV file. And so as a result, we
were no longer touching this stuff.
Uh but again, man, you you were setting
loose these robots on anybody's
computer. You got to keep an eye on
these shenanigans.
Because even if you're kind of solving
the problem you promised you'd solve,
you might be doing it in a way that
makes you look like an
All right.
Now,
this is the big one. This is the weird
one.
Because our whole careers,
we have been rewarded by writing the
code. We write the code. We write more
more code. We write the clever code. Oh,
I got a structure in here. This thing
works. This thing is reliable. This
thing is elaborate, but the performance
is really good. And and man, we just got
to code the out of this thing. If
we code our way out of this problem,
everything's going to be great, right?
That is not the world that we live in
anymore.
And
a very funny thing about code
is that if today you have written some
code that you think is good, and
tomorrow a new model drops,
the code that you wrote has the exact
same value.
If anything, it might be declining a
bit, right? Code has always been
a depreciating asset. You write it, you
might ship it into the world a little
bit rotten cuz it's got some tech debt,
and you got to deal with that at some
point. But meanwhile, you shipped on
time, you got what you had to do.
The wizard
that makes everybody so happy
is 90% markdown files,
8%
tools for delivering and processing
markdown files,
And then the rest is like Agent Harness
stuff, right?
Plain text prose
is where so much of our value now lives.
When you write great prose today,
and tomorrow, and even better model
drops, it's going to be able to take
that prose and do even more with it.
And so,
an agent is an octopus, right? It can
wiggle, it can squeeze into tight
corners, it can maneuver itself around
problems. You do not want to
over-constrain
the agent in its ability to get problems
done, aside from the shenanigans stuff
as we talked about, right?
So, instead of thinking about like, man,
how can I scaffold the hell out of the
behavior of this agent? It's about
saying, how do I step back?
How do I give it enough information?
And how do I sequence the information
that I give it so that it does the thing
that I want it to do,
and it makes people happy
in the process.
So, this is what I know
from the robot bloodying my nose.
I see on my clock here, I got a couple
minutes left. Does anyone have questions
about the strange adventure
of building this robot that makes people
happy?
Shoot.
>> Uh
you had in the model airplane section,
>> Yeah.
>> you sort of talked through
giving a sort of like
exact R for the model which was really
helpful for us to have a match to figure
out like what. Is that distributed in
part of the prompt? How how how
Basically, how's that structured in the
mind of
>> Oh, sure. So, the way that we drive
context for the wizard is we use skill
files that are generated from our
context service. And so, that context
service is going to take all of those
model airplanes, flatten them into a
single markdown file, and then include
them as a reference in the skill file.
And so we always have access to the full
model airplane which the model can grep
and otherwise churn through.
Oh, sure.
So, yeah, this is just part of the
supplemental content that is included in
the skill. And so what we found was
there was a range of useful input that
we can include as part of the skill
file. So, we've got documentation which
is plain text prose, but then we also
include the model airplane so that it
can see the shape of a successful
integration and it references all of
that as part of getting the job done.
Shoot.
Oh, sure. So, this uses the Claude agent
SDK which we then wrap inside of a CLI
and so you just run a single command and
then we give you free inference by
logging into PostHog. We've got this LLM
gateway where we can cover all of the
tokens on your behalf
which was a whole zoo because sometimes
Claude code would store off information
in a place that we weren't expecting and
then it would just break for people.
It's it's early days for doing this as
kind of a service.
Anything else I can tell you?
Well, then I'm going to scoot out of the
next speaker's way. Thank you for
hanging out. It's great to see you. Have
yourself a great rest of your day.
>> Hey.